Guide to the George N. Caylor Papers TAM.030
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
George N. Caylor Papers
1903-1973
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Caylor, George Nathan, 1885-1973
TAM.030
1 Linear Feet (2 boxes)
George N. Caylor (1885-1973), born George N. Cohen, was a clothing-industry businessman, labor arbitrator, socialist and the brother of labor leader and socialist Joseph E. Cohen (1883-1950). The collection includes sketches of socialist and labor figures, and other writings concerning labor, socialism, and racial justice. Included is a manuscript of an 800-page indexed autobiography, "If My Memory Serves Me Right," that discusses Caylor's early years in Philadelphia, the socialist movement, the single-tax community of Arden, Delaware, the Rand School of Social Science, and numerous personalities on the left. There is also a 142-page manuscript, "Brother Joe: Fragmentary Chapters for a Life of Joseph E. Cohen," about Caylor's brother, including Cohen's socialism and his relations with Socialist Party leader Eugene V. Debs and Debs' brother and secretary, Theodore. Part of collection deals with Caylor's series of letters to the editor of the Orlando Sentinel on political and social issues that became the subject of a seminar at Rollins College in 1958. Scattered throughout are related clippings.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by George N. Caylor in 1957 and 1965. The accession number associated with these gifts is 1957.002.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
George N. Caylor (1885-1973), born George N. Cohen, was a clothing-industry businessman, labor arbitrator for the War Labor Board during World War II, socialist and the brother of labor leader and Socialist Party activist Joseph E. Cohen (1883-1950).
Joseph E. Cohen was a longtime member of the Socialist Party and a leading member of its Philadelphia organization. In the first decade of the 20th century, he lived for a time, along with his brother George, at Arden (Delaware), founded as a single-tax community, but whose members included many socialists. He was a member of the executive board of the Philadelphia local of the International Typographical Union, served in the 1930s on the Federal Advisory Council of the U.S. Employment Service, and was one of three U.S. labor delegates to 1938 conference of the International Labor Organization.
Scope and Content Note
The collection contains manuscripts of writings, and clippings. The manuscripts include sketches of socialist and labor figures, and other writings concerning labor, socialism, and racial justice, and a manuscript of an 800-page indexed autobiography, "If My Memory Serves Me Right," that discusses Caylor's early years in Philadelphia, the socialist movement, the single-¬tax community of Arden, Delaware, the Rand School of Social Science, his business career and travels, and numerous personalities on the left. There is also a 142-page manuscript, "Brother Joe: Fragmentary Chapters for a Life of Joseph E. Cohen," about Caylor's brother, including Cohen's socialism and his relations with Socialist Party leader Eugene V. Debs and Debs' brother and secretary, Theodore. Part of collection deals with Caylor's series of letters to the editor of the Orlando Sentinel on political and social issues that became the subject of a seminar at Rollins College in 1958. Scattered throughout are related clippings. Caylor's writings include information on Louis Adamic, Joseph E. Cohen, Eugene V. Debs, Elizabeth Gurley Flynn, Clinton S. Golden, Emanuel Haldeman-Julius, Morris Hillquit, Jack London, Pauline Newman, Frances Perkins, Rose Schneiderman, John Spargo, and Bettina Borrman Wells.
Arrangement
The folders are arranged alphabetically.
The files are grouped into 1 series:
Missing Title
I, Papers, 1903-1973.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
George N. Caylor Photographs (PHOTOS 015)
Single tax.; Race discrimination -- United States.; Socialism |z Pennsylvania |z Philadelphia.; Socialism -- United States.; Labor -- United States.; Clippings (information artifacts); Arbitrators, Industrial |z United States.; Philadelphia (Pa.).; Arden (Del.); Biographies.; Autobiographies.; Rollins College (Winter Park, Fla.); Flynn, Elizabeth Gurley; Socialist Party of Philadelphia; Socialist Party (U.S.); Orlando sentinel; Debs, Eugene V. (Eugene Victor), 1855-1926; Hillquit, Morris, 1869-1933; Debs, Theodore, 1864-1945; Cohen, Joseph E., 1883-1950; Adamic, Louis, 1899-1951; Spargo, John, 1876-1966.; Wells, Bettina Borrman; International Typographical Union. Local 2 (Philadelphia, Pa.); Perkins, Frances, 1880-1965.; Schneiderman, Rose, 1882-1972; London, Jack, 1876-1916; Newman, Pauline.; Golden, Clinton S. (Clinton Strong), 1888-1961; Rand School of Social Science; Haldeman-Julius, E. (Emanuel), 1888-1951; Caylor, George Nathan, 1885-1973
- Series I: Papers, 1903-1973.
  - "A", 1970, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Berkman, Aaron, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Berman, Henry, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "Brother Joe: Fragmentary Chapters for a Life of Joseph E. Cohen", undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "Chance and James Simms", undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Cohen, Joseph E., 1903-1920, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Debs, Eugene Victor, 1966, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "Frances Perkins, My Brother Joe, My Wife Tema and Myself: Out of the Memory of George N. Caylor" (4 pp.), undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Goebel, George H., 1963 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Golden, Clinton S., undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "I", undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - "If Memory Serves Me Right": Chapters 1-4, pp. 1-172, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - "If Memory Serves Me Right": Chapters 5-12, pp. 173-382, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - "If Memory Serves Me Righ": Chapters 14-22, pp. 383-576, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Libros, Simon; Long, Fred, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Minassian, Philip, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - New York Call Articles, 1916, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - "Notes for a Talk on My Connection with the Labor Movement", undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Orlando Sentinel: Letters to, 1957-1959 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Perkins, Frances, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "S", undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - "Seventy to Eighty" (Addition to Biography): pp. 577-656, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - "Seventy to Eighty" (Addition to Biography): pp. 657-741, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - "Seventy to Eighty" (Addition to Biography): pp. 742-809, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - "Seventy to Eighty" (Addition to Biography): pp. 810-893, plus Index, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Social Democrats, USA, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - "T", undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - "The Unhappiest Thing I Ever Did", undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - "A Visit with John Spargo", undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Wells, Bettina, 1908-1960, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - "The Word Is Route, Young Man", undated (Box 2, Folder 18)